let A and R be positive real numbers
with r less than 1 the curves Y = X and
Y = - RX + a intersect at the point x =
a 1+ r the distance from the origin to
the Y intercept of- RX + a is a and
because the horizontal distance to yal X
forms an isoceles triangle that distance
is a as well the distance between the
two functions at xal a is a r and again
using properties of isoceles triangles
we see that this horizontal distance is
also a r if we keep spiraling around we
can verify that the vertical and then
sub quent horizontal distances are all
of the form a * R the n as n increases
and because R is less than 1 we see that
this spiral converges to the
intersection point of the two curves if
we focus on the horizontal distances
only we see that a minus a r plus a r 2
- a r cub and so on represents the
length of a line segment whose length is
also given by the x coordinate of the
intersection point a over 1+ R so the
alternating geometric series with first
term a and ratio R has a sum of a over 1
plus r